Some wounds you cannot see.
Lee is a history, drama, war film directed by Ellen Kuras.
The true story of photographer Elizabeth "Lee" Miller, a fashion model who became an
acclaimed war correspondent for Vogue magazine during World War II.
Elizabeth 'Lee' Miller, played by Kate Winslet.
David E. Scherman, played by Andy Samberg.
Roland Penrose, played by Alexander Skarsgård.
Solange D'Ayen, played by Marion Cotillard.
Audrey Withers, played by Andrea Riseborough.
Nusch Eluard, played by Noémie Merlant.
Lee is a 2023 British biographical war drama film directed by Ellen Kuras in her feature directorial debut, from a screenplay by Liz Hannah, John Collee
and Marion Hume, and story from Hume, Collee and Lem Dobbs, adapted from the 1985 biography The Lives of Lee Miller by Antony Penrose.
It stars Kate Winslet as WWII journalist Lee Miller.
The cast includes Marion Cotillard, Andrea Riseborough, Andy Samberg, Noémie
Merlant, Josh O'Connor and Alexander Skarsgård in supporting roles.
The movie took eight years to make and, at one point, due to precarious funding, Winslet (who
also produced the movie) paid the entire cast and crew's salaries for two weeks.
The film made its world premiere at the Toronto
International Film Festival on 9 September 2023.
It was released theatrically in the United Kingdom
by Sky Cinema on 13 September 2024.
Lee received generally positive reviews from critics and
became Sky UK's highest-grossing original film.
It grossed $24.6 million worldwide.
For her performance in the film, Winslet received nominations for Best
Actress at the Golden Globe Awards and AACTA International Awards.
Additionally, the film received a nomination from
BAFTA for Outstanding British Film.
The film explores themes of nazi, photographer,
photography, concentration camp, holocaust (shoah).
The tone is emotional.